rolex.com 2019-09-20

# Privacy Notice

## Introduction

Rolex respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

## Controller

When we mention “Rolex”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice, we are referring to:  
ROLEX SA  
3-5-7 rue François-Dussaud  
1211 Geneva 26  
Switzerland

Swiss company number: CH-660.0.012.920-4

ROLEX SA is the controller for personal data collected via this website.

## Personal Data Supervisor

We have appointed a personal data supervisor who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the personal data supervisor using the following details.

Personal Data Supervisor: Mr. Xavier Braun  
Postal address: 3-5-7, rue François-Dussaud, 1211 Geneva 26, Switzerland  
Telephone number: +4122 302 22 00  
Email address: privacy@rolex.com  
ROLEX SA only responds to enquiries concerning data protection. Please send any communications in either English or French.

## Supervisory Authority

You also have the right to make a complaint at any time to the supervisory authority in the appropriate jurisdiction.

## The Data We Collect About You

Personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

• **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.

• **Contact Data** includes address, email address and telephone numbers.

• **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.

• **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website.

• **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

## How is your personal data collected?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

• **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Marketing and Communications Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise.

• **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. Please see our cookie policy for further details.

• **Third parties.** We will receive personal data about you from various third parties as set out below:

• Analytics solutions from the following parties:  
        • Adobe Analytics based in Ireland  
        • Content Square based in France

• Technical monitoring solution from the following party:  
        • New Relic based in the USA

• Maps services from the following parties:  
        • Google Maps based in the USA  
        • Baidu Maps based in China

## Purposes for which we will use your personal data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**_Purpose-Activity_** **/** Notifying you about changes to our privacy notice  
**_Type of data_** / (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Marketing and Communications  
**_Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest /  _** (a) Performance of a contract with you (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation (c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated)  
**_Retention period_ _/_** 12 months

**_Purpose-Activity_ _/_** To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  
**_Type of data_ _/_** (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical  
**_Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest /_** (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
**_Retention period /_** 12 months

**_Purpose-Activity /_** To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences  
**_Type of data /_** (a) Technical (b) Usage  
**_Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest /_** Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
_**Retention period** **/**_ 25 months

**_Purpose-Activity /_** To provide you with marketing communication and information about our company and products  
**_Type of data /_** (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Marketing and Communications  
**_Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest /_** (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business) (b) Consent  
**_Retention period_ /** Following notification that the data subject no longer wishes to receive marketing communications

## Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

## Data Retention

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are set out in the table above.

## Marketing

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of activities/purposes 1-4 above.

## Discolures of your personal Data

Subject to your consent, we may share your personal data with internal and external third parties.

In any case, we require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

## International Transfers

We share your personal data within the Rolex group of companies. This may involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area **(EEA)**.

Some of our external third parties are based outside the EEA so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

• We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see [European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)

• Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en)

• Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the US. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en)

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

## Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

## Cookies & third-party links

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see here.

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

## Your legal rights

Under certain circumstances, you have the following rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data:

• **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

• **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

• **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

• **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

• **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:

\- If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy.  
\- Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it.  
\- Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.  
\- You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

• **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

• **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact the personal data supervisor.

## No fee usually required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

## What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

## Time limit to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

## Your duty to inform us of changes

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
